A finding aid to the Hildreth Meière papers, 1901-2011, bulk 1911-1960 in the Archives of American Art AAA.meiemari
Archives of American Art
- Travel Records, 1933-1958; Series 5; 9.8 Linear feet Boxes 6-10, 15, 28-33, OV 18
  - Slides, 1946-1958; 5.2 (Box 6)
    - Scandinavia (Box 9)
      - Set 2, circa 1951 (Box 9, Folder 11-17)
        Subjects depicted include Denmark, Holland, Sweden, and may also include Italy among unidentified slides.
    - South America (Box 10)
      - Notes, circa 1947 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Slides, circa 1947; 2 slide boxes (Box 10, Folder 2-3)
        Locations depicted in Columbia, Ecuador, and Peru.
    - Spain, circa 1950 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Thailand (Box 10)
      - Lists and Notes, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Set 1, 1952; 2 slide boxes (Box 10, Folder 6-7)
      - Set 2, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Motion Picture Film, 1933-1958; 5.3
    There are 83 motion picture films shot by Hildreth Meiere while traveling between 1933 and 1958. Many of the same trips are represented in the footage as are shown in the slides in the collection, including the 1946 trip to Mexico and Guatemala, the 1947 trip to South America (Columbia, Ecuador, Peru), the 1949-1950 trip to Europe (France, Switzerland, Austria, Holland, Belgium, and Italy), the 1951 trip to Scandinavia (Finland, Norway, Sweden), the 1952-1953 "Grand Tour" (Australia, New Zealand, Indonesia, Thailand, Ceylon, India, Rhodesia, Congo, South Africa, Italy, England, Scotland, Ireland, and France), the 1954 "Holy Land" trip (Egypt, Greece, Israel, Lebanon, Syria, Turkey), and the 1958 trip to Belgium.
    Unique to this series is documentation of earlier trips to Turkey (1933), Germany (1934), Europe (1936, Germany, Poland, Russia), and two shipboard films made on the S.S. America (1940) and on an Odyssey cruise (1938), which retraced the steps of Homer's Odyssey.
    Film reels have been arranged by trip where possible, except for the countries on the "Grand Tour," which are arranged by country. Where multiple European countries are found on a single reel, they are filed under Europe.
    - Notes, circa 1939-1955 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Africa (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Rhodesia and Congo, 1953; 1 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 10, Item 1)
      - South Africa, 1952-1953; 3 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 10, Item 2)
    - Australia and New Zealand, 1952; 3 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Belgium, 1958; 1 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 12)
      Film reels housed in Box 28; See also "Europe; Holland, Belgium, France."
      See also "Europe; Holland, Belgium, France"
    - Ceylon, 1952; 2 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Europe; Germany, Poland, Russia, 1936; 1 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Europe; France, Switzerland, Austria, 1949-1950; 1 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 15, Item 1)
    - Europe; Holland, Belgium, France, 1949-1950; 1 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 15, Item 2)
      Film reels housed in Box 29
    - France, 1949-1950; 1 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 16, Item 1)
    - France, 1953; 1 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 16, Item 2)
    - Germany, 1934; 2 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 17)
      Film housed in box 29
      See also "Europe; Germany, Poland, Russia"
    - Great Britain (Box 10, Folder 18)
      - England, 1953; 3 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 18, Item 1)
      - Ireland, 1953; 1 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 18, Item 2)
      - Scotland, 1953; 2 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 18, Item 3)
      - Unspecified Location, 1953; 1 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 18, Item 4)
    - Holy Land (Box 10, Folder 19)
      - Egypt, 1954; 2 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 19, Item 1)
      - Greece, 1954; 1 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 19, Item 2)
      - Israel, 1954; 2 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 19, Item 3)
        Film housed in boxes 29 and 30
      - Lebanon and Syria, 1954; 1 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 19, Item 4)
        Film housed in box 30
      - Turkey, 1954; 1 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 19, Item 4)
    - India, 1952; 3 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - India to Africa, 1952; 3 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Indonesia, 1952; 3 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Italy, 1949-1950; 6 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Italy, 1953; 2 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 24)
      Film housed in box 31
    - Mexico and Guatemala, 1946; 17 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 25)
      Film housed in boxes 31 and 32
    - Scandanavia (Box 10, Folder 26)
      - Finland, 1951; 1 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 26, Item 1)
        Film housed in box 32
      - Norway, 1951; 3 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 26, Item 2)
      - Sweden, 1951; 2 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 26, Item 3)
      - Unspecified location, 1951; 2 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 26, Item 4)
    - South America (Box 10, Folder 27)
      - Columbia, 1947; 1 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 27, Item 1)
      - Ecuador, 1947; 1 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 27, Item 2)
      - Peru, 1947; 2 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 27, Item 3)
    - Thailand, 1952; 2 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Turkey, 1933; 1 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 29)
      Film housed in box 33; see also "Holy Land."
    - Shipboard Films (Box 10, Folder 30)
      See also "India to Africa"
      - S.S. America, 1940; 2 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 30, Item 1)
        Film housed in box 33
      - Odyssey, 1938; 1 Film reels 16mm (Box 10, Folder 30, Item 2)
    - FIlm reels from Box 10, Folder 10, Item 1 through Box 10, Folder 15, Item 1 (Box 28)
    - Film Reels from Box 10, Folder 15, Item 2 through Box 10, Folder 19, Item 3 (Box 29)
    - Film Reels from Box 10, Folder 19, Item 3 through Box 10, Folder 23 (Box 30)
    - Film Reels from Box 10, Folder 24 through Box 10, Folder 25 (Box 31)
    - Film Reels from Box 10, Folder 25 through Box 10, Folder 28 (Box 32)
    - Film Reels from Box 10, Folder 29 through Box 10, Folder 30 (Box 33)
- Printed Materials, 1913-1998; Series 6; 2.1 Linear feet Boxes 10-12, 15
  Series contains clippings, exhibition catalogs, invitations, announcements, pamphlets, periodicals, an educational film, postcards of the 1934 passion play in Oberammergau attended by Meière, directories and publications of professional organizations to which Meière belonged, publications about commissioned works by Meière, and reproductions of works by Meière. Most of the periodicals and clippings contain some reference to Meière or a specific work by her, and several periodicals contain articles written by her. Many of the publications in this series date from after Meière's death, and were gathered by her daughter and grandaughter in the course of research into her works.
  Periodicals are arranged by the title of the serial, with notes to indicate specific works addressed in the publication if appropriate. Publications regarding a single work or structure containing works by Meière are grouped together at the end of the series. See also Series 5, Travel Records, for printed materials related to Meière’s travel. Additional printed material is found in Series 1, Biographical Material.
  - Book, Santillana del Mar y Altamira, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Clippings, circa 1920-1955 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Clippings, 1916-1921 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Clippings, 1922-1923 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Clippings, 1924-1925 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Clippings, 1926-1927 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Clippings, 1928 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Clippings, 1929 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Clippings, 1930-1931 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Clippings, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 39-40)
  - Clippings, 1933 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Clippings, 1934 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Clippings, 1935 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Clippings, 1936 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Clippings, 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1939-1940 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1941-1942 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1943-1945 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1946-1951 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 6-7)
  - Clippings, 1953-1958 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, 1959-1961 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, 1974-1981 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, 1982-1988 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, 1990-1998 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Exhibition Catalogs (Box 11)
    - Miniature Rooms by Narcissa Thorne, 1933-1941; 6 bound volumes in 5 editions (Box 11, Folder 13-15)
    - National Society of Mural Painters at the Brooklyn Museum, 1925 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - American Art Deco Architecture at the Finch College Museum of Art, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Invitations to Exhibitions, Talks, and Travel Lectures, 2000; 1932-1959 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    Contains an inventory prepared by the donor
  - Menu and Wine List for Fred Harvey Restaurant with Murals by Hildreth Meière, circa 1937 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Pamphlets, Ellen Dunlap Hopkins' "The Progress of Women", 1936 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Periodicals (Box 11)
    - American Architect, 1928 February 5 (Box 11, Folder 21)
      Oversized periodical in box 15
    - The Architectural Forum, 1932 July and October (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Architecture, 1924 October (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Architecture, 1931 May and June (Box 11, Folder 24)
      Articles regarding 1 Wall Street and the Nebraska State Capitol
    - Architecture U.S.S.R., 1935 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Bulletin de la Société Scientifique de Skoplje, 1927-1929 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - The Churchman, 1929 November 23 (Box 11, Folder 27)
      Article regarding St. Bartholomew's
    - Fortune, 1935 July (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Harper's Bazaar, 1938 September 1 (Box 11, Folder 29)
      Article regarding 1939 New York World's Fair
    - The Independent, 1937 July 4 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Independent woman, 1933 February (Box 11, Folder 31)
      Article regarding Rockefeller Center
    - Interior Design and Decoration, 1940 September (Box 11, Folder 32)
      Article regarding the S.S. America
    - Jar-Ptitza (The Fire Bird), 1921 (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Journal of the Associated Alumnae of the Sacred Heart, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Journal of the American Institute of Architects, 1956 May (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Manhattanville College Publications, 1921-1961 (Box 11, Folder 36-37)
    - The Masses, 1913 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Metropolitan Museum Annual Report, 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Pencil Points, 1927 March (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Pictorial Review, 1926 September (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Shipyard Bulletin, 1951-1952 (Box 11, Folder 42)
      Articles concerning the S.S. United States
    - Soviet Travel, circa 1936 (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Survey Graphic, 1928 October (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - V.O.K.S. (Organe de la Société pour Relations Culturelles entre L'U.R.S.S. et l'Etranger), 1930 April (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - The Western Architect, 1927 April (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - Women's City Club Magazine (San Francisco), 1927-1939 (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - Port Jackson, Educational Film about Sydney, Australia, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Film reel housed in box 33
  - Postcards of Oberammergau Passion Play, 1934 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Professional Organizations (Box 12)
    - Architectural League of New York, Exhibition Catalog, 1930 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      Oversized publication in box 15
    - Architectural League of New York, Index of Exhibits, 1921-1933 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Art Students League, Course Catalogs, 1928-1944 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Cor Ardens By-Laws, circa 1921 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - National Society of Mural Painters, Directory, 1936 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Publications Regarding Works by Hildreth Meière (Box 12)
    - Oscar S. Straus Memorial Volume, Memorial Tryptich, 1949 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Church and Temple Brochures and Publications, 1988-1998 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Corporate Brochures and Newsletters, 1956-1985 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Cathedral of St. Louis, 1988-1994 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Maryland Cathedral, 1920 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - National Academy of Sciences, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Nebraska Capitol, 1926-1934; 1978; 1954 (Box 12, Folder 13-14)
    - Rockefeller Center, 1986-1994 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - S.S. United States, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - St. Michael's Monastery Church, 1936 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Reproductions of Hildreth Meière Works, 1930-1996 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    Oversized printer's proofs in box 15
  - Oversized Periodicals from Box 11, Folders 21, 28, 30, 38, and 41 (Box 15)
  - Oversized Professional Organization Publiation from Box 12, Folder 3 (Box 15)
  - Oversized Publications Regarding Works by Hildreth Meière from Box 12, Folders 11 and 12 (Box 15)
  - Oversized Reproductions of Hildreth Meière Works (Box 15)
  - Film Reel from Box 12, Folder 1 (Box 33)
- Photographs and Moving Images, circa 1915-1966; Series 7; 5.3 Linear feet Boxes 12-13, 16-17, 20-27
  Digital copies of films of the 1939 New York World's Fair, the D.C. Municipal Center Frieze, and the documentary "The Making of a Triptych" are available for research use. Projection prints of 1939 New York World's Fair films and the film of the Municipal Center Frieze are also available for loan.
  Photographs and moving images include personal photographs and home movies of Meière, family, and associates, and photographs and motion picture film of artworks by Meière and others. In addition to printed photographs, negatives, slides, and transparencies, this series contains 311 lantern slides, 201 glass negatives, 8 original film reels, and duplicates of those film reels on 8 film reels and 2 videocassettes (HDCAM).
  Personal photographs include numerous portraits of Meière throughout her life, from her time in school to her time in the U. S. Navy during WWI, and later portraits taken by Peter A. Juley and Sons and Berenice Abbott. Other personal photographs are found with childhood friend Katherine Harvey in costume, as well as autographed theatrical photographs of actresses Marjorie Patterson and Margaret Anglin by Sarony and Charles Frohman. A motion picture film contains home movies shot in 1926 in New York City. Family slides of homes and family members are also found, along with photographs of Meière with personal and professional associates, including formal group photos of annual New York City Arts Commission dinners, Meière accepting her honorary doctorate at Manhattanville College, and Meière riding camels in Egypt.
  Photographed artworks by Meière include snapshots of sketches for some of her earliest commissions from 1924, lantern slides and copy negatives of later commissions, lantern slides and glass negatives of a series of drawings Meière made of the 1934 performance of the passion play in Oberammergau, Germany, as well as murals in Oberammergau, motion picture film of Meière’s and other artists' murals and sculptures at the 1939 New York World’s Fair, and motion picture film of the Municipal Center Frieze in Washington, DC. Triptychs created by Meière during WWII, mainly for the Citizen’s committee for the Army and Navy, are documented in a film documentary, "The Making of a Triptych," and in 25 color lantern slides and color transparencies. Numerous photographs of various commissions by Meière are also found.
  Photographed artworks by others include a bust of Meière by James Drummond Herbert, slides of the Brussels Fair of 1958, slides of cave paintings in Italy, France, and Lebanon; a set of slides of Flemish paintings, and a large set of glass copy negatives and lantern slides of murals in Norway, possibly taken during Meière’s 1932 trip to Scandinavia. A reel of film shot at the Paris Fair of 1937 is also found.
  Glass plate copy negatives and lantern slides in this series are housed separately. Glass copy negatives are closed to researchers.
  See also Series 5, Travel Records, for a very large series of slides and motion picture film, which includes images of mosaics, architecture, and international fairs. Additional photographs are also found in Series 1, Biographical Material, in the Dunns’ research on Meière’s Century of Progress Murals from the Chicago World's Fair of 1933-1934.
  - Personal Photographs (Box 12)
    - Portraits of Hildreth Meière, circa 1915-1920 (Box 12, Folder 19)
      Includes U.S. Navy portraits
    - Portraits of Hildreth Meière, circa 1920-1940 (Box 12, Folder 20)
      Includes photographs by Peter A. Juley & Son and Francis Bruguiere; oversized photographs in box 16
    - Portraits of Hildreth Meière, circa 1941-1960 (Box 12, Folder 21)
      Includes a photograph by Berenice Abbott; oversized photographs in box 16
    - Class Photograph, Manhattanville College, 1911 (Box 12, Folder 22)
      Oversized photograph in box 16
    - Hildreth Meière and Katherine Harvey in Costume, circa 1915 (Box 12, Folder 23)
      Oversized photographs in box 16
    - Hildreth Meière with Others, circa 1920-1955 (Box 12, Folder 24)
      Includes photographs from honorary doctorate ceremony, 1953, and Meière in Egypt, 1954; oversized photographs in box 16
    - Family Slides, circa 1950; Includes 1 slide box (Box 12, Folder 25-27)
    - Family Slides, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Home Movies, 1926 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Autographed Photographs of Actors, circa 1917 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Photographs and Moving Images of Artwork by Hildreth Meière (Box 12)
    - 1939 New York World’s Fair, "Construction of a Frieze", 1 Film reels original, black and white 16mm; 1 Film reels Duplicate internegative 16mm; 1 Film reels Duplicate, projection print 16mm (Box 12, Folder 31, Item 1)
      Original film reels in box 33, duplicate internegatives and projection prints in box 17; includes notes listing mural painters pictured in film.
    - 1939 New York World's Fair, Murals and Sculptures, 2 Film reels Original, kodachrome color 16mm; 2 Film reels Duplicate internegative 16mm; 2 Film reels Duplicate, projection prints 16mm (Box 12, Folder 31, Item 2)
      Original film reels in box 33, duplicate internegatives and projection prints in box 17; see also Various Commissions for lantern slides of the World's Fair
    - Drawing of the Annunciation, circa 1930 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Municipal Center Frieze, circa 1941; 1 Film reels Original, Kodachrome color 16mm; 1 Film reels Duplicate internegative 16mm; 1 Film reels Duplicate projection print 16mm (Box 12, Folder 33)
      Original film reels in box 33, duplicate internegatives and projection prints in box 17
    - Oberammagau Murals, Passion Play Sketches, and Source Material, 1934; 16 glass copy negatives and 43 lantern slides (Box 12, Folder 34)
      Glass negatives and lantern slides housed in box 20
    - Triptychs (Box 13)
      - "Making of a Triptych," Documentary, circa 1943; 2 Videocassettes (HDCAM) Duplicates; 2 Film reels Original, Kodachrome color 16mm (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
        Film reels housed in box 33
      - Photographs of Triptychs, 1942-1966; 25 Lantern slides; 43 Color transparencies (Box 13, Folder 3)
        Includes inventory; lantern slides are housed in box 21
    - Various Commissions (Box 13)
      - Copy Negatives and Lantern Slides, 1936-1938; 97 Lantern slides; 79 Negatives (photographic) (Box 13, Folder 4-5)
        Subjects include St. Mark's Church (Mt. Kisco), National Academy of Sciences, Nebraska State Capitol, St. Paul's Church (New Haven), 1 Wall Street, AT&T Long Distance Building, Century of Progress International Exposition, St. Michael's Monastery Church (Union City, NJ), Westport Room of Fred Harvey Restaurant (Kansas City, MO), St. Bartholemew's (New York), 1939 New York World's Fair, among others; lantern slides housed in boxes 22-23
      - Prints, circa 1924-1960 (Box 13, Folder 6)
        Subjects include National Academy of Sciences, Nebraska State Capital, One Wall Street, The Westport Room Murals, Fred Harvey Restaurant, World’s Fair Murals, S. S. America Dining Room Decorations, Prudential Life Insurance Mural, Traveler's Insurance Mosaic; oversized prints in box 16.
      - Slides, Cathedral of St. Louis, circa 1958 (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - Snapshots of Preparatory Drawings, circa 1924 (Box 13, Folder 8)
        Subjects include Nebraska State Capital, National Academy of Sciences, St. Martin’s of Providence, R.I., and one unidentified design.
  - Photographs and Moving Images of Artwork by Others (Box 13)
    - Brussels Fair, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 9)
      See also Belgium slides and motion picture film in Series 5, Travel Records
    - Bust of Hildreth Meière by James D. Herbert, circa 1940 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Cave Paintings in Italy, France, and Lebanon, circa 1950; 1 slide box (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Flemish Paintings, circa 1950-1958; 1 slide box (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Norwegian Murals, circa 1932; 106 Glass negatives copy negatives; 146 Lantern slides (Box 13, Folder 13)
      Lantern slides housed in boxes 24 and 25; glass copy negatives housed in boxes 26 and 27
    - Paris Fair, 1937; 1 Film reels 16mm (Box 13, Folder 14)
      File Plan note
    - Unidentified Artworks, circa 1948; 60 Negatives (photographic) Copy negatives (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Oversized Personal Photographs from Box 12, Folders 20, 21, 22, 23, 24, and 30 (Box 16)
  - Oversized Photographic Prints of Various Commissions by Hildreth Meière from Box 13, Folder 6 (Box 16)
  - Duplicate Film Reels from Box 12, Folder 31, Items 1 and 2; and Box 12, Folder 33 (Box 17)
  - Glass Negatives and Lantern Slides from Box 12, Folder 34 (Box 20)
  - Lantern Slides from Box 13, Folder 3 (Box 21)
  - Lantern Slides from Box 13, Folders 4-5 (Box 22-23)
  - Lantern Slides from Box 13, Folder 13 (Box 24-25)
  - Glass Copy Negatives from Box 13, Folder 13 (Box 26-27)
  - Original Film Reels from Box 12, Folder 31, Items 1 and 2; Box 12, Folder 33; Box 13, Folder 1; and Box 13, Folder 14 (Box 33)
- Sketchbooks, 1911- circa 1922; Series 8; 0.4 Linear feet Box 13
  There are eight sketchbooks containing figure studies, landscapes, and notes. One undated volume contains mainly costume sketches and handwritten notes. One sketchbook contains scenes from Yosemite National Park from 1912. Three of the sketchbooks appear to be from a continuous period of travel in Europe in 1912 and 1913, with sketches from Italy, France, and England, many identified and dated. A sketchbook labeled “Art Students League” contains mainly theatrical and costume studies, some with actors and performances identified from 1912-1913. A Sketchbook labeled “Fort Mason, San Francisco” also contains theatrical studies and notes on art techniques. The latest sketchbook is labeled “Navy Dept.” and contains portraits of Navy personnel, presumably from Meière’s time in the service, and other figure studies. Also found are notes in another hand, transcribing identifications from within the sketchbooks’ pages.
  Additional drawings and ephemera found in the pages of the sketchbooks have been removed and filed alongside the sketchbook in which they were found. Additional drawings by Meière are found in the illustrated letters of Seres 2, Correspondence.
  - Sketchbook, circa 1911-1922 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Yosemite, 1911-1912 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Italy, 1911-1912 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Italy, 1912 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Italy, France, and London, 1912 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - "Art Students League", 1912-1913 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - "Fort Mason, San Francisco", 1913 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - "Navy Department", circa 1918-1922 (Box 13, Folder 23)